Guide to the Native American subject vertical file [ca.1850-2000.]
Native American subject vertical file
- Associations - Native Seeds Search (Box 20)
- Associations - New Mexico Association on Indian Affairs (Box 20)
- Associations - New York City Indian Association (Box 20)
- Associations - New York State Archaeological Association (Box 20)
- Associations - Northwest Indian Women's Circle (Box 20)
- Associations - Northwest Regional (Box 20)
- Associations - O (Box 20)
- Associations - OHOYO (Box 20)
- Associations - One Sky (Box 20)
- Associations - P (Box 20)
- Associations - Pana Pana (Box 20)
- Associations - Papangu (Box 20)
- Associations - Project Roothold (Box 20)
- Associations - Q (Box 20)
- Associations - R (Box 20)
- Associations - Regional Council of South American Indians (Box 20)
- Associations - Rupert's Land Research Centre (Box 20)
- Associations - S (Box 20)
- Associations - Sequoya League (Box 20)
- Associations - Seventh Generation Fund (Box 20)
- Associations - Society for the Preservation of American Indian Culture (Box 20)
- Associations - Society for the Propagation of the Gospel Among the Indians of North America (Box 20)
- Associations - Society of American Indians (Box 20)
- Association - Southwestern Association on Indian Arts (Box 20)
- Associations - Summer Institute of Linguistics (Box 20)
- Associations - Sunray Meditation Society (Box 20)
- Associations - Survival International U.S.A. (Box 20)
- Associations - T (Box 20)
- Associations - Taino del Norte (Box 20)
- Associations - Techqua Ikachi (Box 20)
- Associations - Thunderbird Dancers (Box 20)
- Associations - U (Box 20)
- Associations - United Indians Development Association (Box 20)
- Associations - United Nations Working Group on Indigenous Populations (Box 20)
- Associations - United Scholarship Service (Box 20)
- Associations - United South and Eastern Tribes Inc. (Box 20)
- Associations - V (Box 20)
- Associations - W (Box 20)
- Associations - WARN (Box 20)
- Associations - Wenner-Gren (Box 20)
- Associations - Western Shoshone National Council (Box 20)
- Associations - Women's National Indian Association (Box 21)
- Associations - Working Group on Indigenous Population (Box 21)
- Associations - X,Y,Z (Box 21)
- Astronomy (Box 21)
- Athapascan Indians (Box 21)
- Atlantis (Box 21)
- Atsina Indians - See also Folklore - Atsina (Box 21)
- Auctions (Box 21)
- Audio Visual Aids 1 (Box 21)
- Audio Visual Aids 2 (Box 21)
- Automation (Box 21)
- Aymara Indians (Bolivia) - See also - Language Aymara (Box 21)
- Aztecs 1 (Box 21)
- Aztecs 2 (Box 21)
- Aztecs 3 (Box 21)
- Aztecs - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 21)
- Aztecs - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 21)
- Aztecs Calendar 1 Includes Luis Enrique Erro Planetarium (Box 22)
- Aztecs Calendar 2 (Box 22)
- Aztecs Calendar - Articles & Corres. (Box 22)
- Aztecs Calendar - Manuscripts 1 (Box 22)
- Aztecs Calendar - Manuscripts 2 (Box 22)
- Aztecs Calendar - Manuscripts 3 (Box 22)
- Aztecs Manuscripts - Oversize (Box 132)
  Codex Xolotl, Histoire Chichimeque. Includes photostats.
- Aztecs Calendar - Manuscripts - Articles & Corres. (Box 22)
- Aztecs Religion (Box 22)
- Baby Carriers (Box 22)
- Backlash Includes Southern Poverty Law Center, Militias, KKK (Box 22)
- Bahamas (Box 22)
- Bahamas - Antiquities (Box 22)
- Bannock Indians (Box 22)
- Bark (Box 22)
- Basket Makers (Box 22)
- Basketry (Box 23)
- Basketry - Articles & Corres. (Box 23)
- Basketry - California (Box 23)
- Basketry - Northeast (Box 23)
- Basketry - Northwest (Box 23)
- Basketry - Plains (Box 23)
- Basketry - South America (Box 23)
- Basketry - Southeast (Box 23)
- Basketry - Southwest (Box 23)
- Basketry - Techniques and Designs (Box 23)
- Beads and Beadwork (Box 23)
- Beads and Beadwork (articles, etc.) (Box 23)
- Belize (Box 23)
- Belize - Antiquities (Box 23)
- Bella Coola Indians (Box 23)
- Beothuk Indians (Box 23)
- Berdache (Box 23)
- Bibliographies (Box 23)
- Bibliographies - Arizona (Box 23)
- Bibliographies - California (Box 23)
- Bibliographies - Central America (Box 23)
- Bibliographies - Children (Box 23)
- Bibliographies - General (Box 23)
- Bibliographies - Kentucky (Box 23)
- Bibliographies - Latin America (Box 23)
- Bibliographies - Mexico (Box 23)
- Bibliographies - Nevada (Box 24)
- Bibliographies - North America 1 (Box 24)
- Bibliographies - North America 2 (Box 24)
- Bibliographies - Periodicals (Box 24)
- Bibliographies - South America (Box 24)
- Bibliographies for the Blind (Box 24)
- Bilingual Education (Box 24)
- Bills (Box 132)
- Biloxi Indians (Siouan) - See also Language - Biloxi (Box 24)
- Blackfoot Indians 1 (Box 24)
- Blackfoot Indians 2 (Box 24)
- Blackfoot Indians 3 (Box 24)
- Blackfeet Indians 4 (Box 132)
- Bolivia (Box 24)
- Bolivia - Antiquities 1 (Box 24)
- Bolivia - Antiquities 2 (Box 24)
- Bolivia - Antiquities 3 (Box 24)
- Bolivia - Articles & Corres. (Box 24)
- Bolivia Indians (Box 25)
- Bolivia Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 25)
- Book Searchers\Reviews (Box 25)
- Bororo Indians (Brazil) - See also Language - Bororo (Box 25)
- Botany (Box 25)
- Botocudo, Indians (Brazil) (Box 25)
- Bow and Arrow - See also Folsom complex; Poisons (Box 25)
- Bow and Arrow - Articles & Corres (Box 25)
- Brazil 1 (Box 25)
- Brazil 2 (Box 25)
- Brazil - Antiquities 1 (Box 25)
- Brazil - Antiquities 2 (Box 25)
- Brazil - Antiquities 3 (Box 25)
- Brazil - History (Box 25)
- Brazil Indians 1 (Box 26)
- Brazil Indians 2 (Box 26)
- Brazil Indians 3 (Box 26)
- Brazil Indians 4 (Box 26)
- Brazil Indians - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 26)
- Brazil Indians - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 26)
- Brazil Indians - Pamphlets (Box 26)
- British Columbia Indians (Box 26)
- British Guiana (Box 26)
- British Guiana - Antiquities (Box 26)
- British Guiana - Indians - See also Language - Accawai; Paramuna Indians (Box 26)
- British Honduras (Box 27)
- British Honduras - Antiquities 1 (Box 27)
- British Honduras - Antiquities 2 (Box 27)
- Bronx (Box 27)
- Brooklyn Museum (Box 27)
- Brotherton Indians (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs (Box 133)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs prior to 1963 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1963 - 1964 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1965 - 1967 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1968 - 1970 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1971 - 1973 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1974 - 1976 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1977 - 1979 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1980 - 1981 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1982 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1983 - 1984 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1985 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1986 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1987 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1988 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1989 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 1990 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs 2000 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 27)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 28)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs Higher Education Programs (Box 132)
- Bureau of Indian Affairs Publications (Box 28)
- Burial Customs (Box 28)
- Bush Negroes (Dutch Guiana) (Box 28)
- Caddo Indians (Box 28)
- Cahuilla Indians (Box 28)
- Caingang Indians (Brazil) (Box 28)
- Calendars 1 (Box 28)
- Calendars 2 (Box 28)
- Calendars 3 (Box 133)
- Calendars - Articles & Corres. (Box 28)
- California - Antiquities 1 (Box 28)
- California - Antiquities 2 (Box 28)
- California - Antiquities - (Central) (Box 28)
- California - Antiquities (Northern) (Box 28)
- California - Antiquities (Southern) 1 (Box 29)
- California - Antiquities (Southern) 2 (Box 29)
- California - History 1 (Box 29)
- California - History 2 (Box 29)
- California - Indians 1 (Box 29)
- California - Indians 2 (Box 29)
- California - Indians (Southern) (Box 29)
- California - Indians - Legislation (Box 29)
- Campa Indians - Peru (Box 29)
- Canada 1 (Box 29)
- Canada 2 (Box 29)
- Canada - Articles & Corres. (Box 29)
- Canada - Antiquities 1 (Box 30)
- Canada - Antiquities 2 (Box 30)
- Canada - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 30)
- Canada - Antiquities - British Columbia (Box 30)
- Canada - Antiquities - Ontario 1 (Box 30)
- Canada - Antiquities - Ontario 2 (Box 30)
- Canada - Antiquities - Ontario - Articles & Corres. (Box 30)
- Canada - Antiquities - Quebec (Box 30)
- Canada - Eskimo 1 (Box 30)
- Canada - Eskimo 2 (Box 30)
- Canada - History 1 (Box 30)
- Canada - History 2 (Box 31)
- Canada - History - Article & Corres. (Box 31)
- Canada - Indians 1 (Box 31)
- Canada - Indians 2 (Box 31)
- Canada - Indians 3 (Box 31)
- Canada - Indians - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 31)
- Canada - Indians - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 31)
- Canada - Indians - Government Relations (Box 31)
- Canarsie Indians (Box 31)
- Cannibalism, Scalping and Head Trophies - See also Jivaro Indians (Box 31)
- Captivities (Box 31)
- Captivities - Articles & Corres. (Box 31)
- Caraja Indians - Brazil - See also Language - Caraja (Box 31)
- Career Opportunities (Box 31)
- Carib Indians (C.A., S.A., W.I.) - See also Language - Carib (Box 31)
- Carib Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 32)
- Carrier Indians (Athapasean) (Box 32)
- Cataloging and Classification (Box 32)
- Cataloging and Classification - Articles & Corres. (Box 32)
- Catalogs of Exhibitions (Box 32)
- Catalogs of Exhibitions - Articles & Corres. (Box 32)
- Catawba Indians (Siouan) 1 - See also Language - Catawba (Box 32)
- Catawba Indians (Siouan) 2 - See also Language - Catawba (Box 32)
- Cayapa Indians - See also Language, Cayapa (Box 32)
- Cayuga Indians (Iroquois) (Box 32)
- Census (Box 32)
- Central America (Box 32)
- Central America - Antiquities 1 (Box 32)
- Central America - Antiquities 2 (Box 32)
- Central America - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 32)
- Central America - History (Box 32)
- Central America - Indians (Box 32)
- Central America - Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 32)
- Ceremonies and Dances 1 (Box 33)
- Ceremonies and Dances 2 (Box 33)
- Ceremonies and Dances 3 (Box 33)
- Ceremonies and Dances - Articles & Corres. (Box 33)
- Chemehuevi Indians (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Art (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Bibliography (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Census (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Conferences (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Correspondence (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Economics (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Education (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Food (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Genealogy (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Government Relations (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Health (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - History (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Implements and Weapons (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Legal Documents (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Manuscripts (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Medicine (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Oversize (Box 131)
- Cherokee Indians - Rites and Ceremonies (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Social Life and Customs (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Tourism (Box 33)
- Cherokee Indians - Tribal Government (Box 33)
- Cheyenne Indians (Box 34)
- Cheyenne Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 34)
- Chibcha Indians (Colombia) (Box 34)
- Chickasaw Indians (Muskogean) (Box 34)
- Chichimecs (Mexico) (Box 34)
- Child Welfare (Box 34)
- Children 1 (Box 34)
- Children 2 (Box 34)
- Chile (Box 34)
- Chile - Antiquities 1 - See also Tierra del Fuego (Box 34)
- Chile - Antiquities 2 - See also Tierra del Fuego (Box 34)
- Chile - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 35)
- Chile - Indians - See also Araucanian Indians; Tierra del Fuego - Indians (Box 35)
- Chinantec Indians (Mexico) - See also Language - Chinantec (Box 35)
- Chinook Indians (Box 35)
- Chipewyan Indians (Athapascan) - See also Folklore - Chipewyan (Box 35)
- Chippewa Economics (Box 35)
- Chippewa Indians 1 (Box 35)
- Chippewa Indians 1 (Box 35)
- Chippewa Indians - Government Relations (Box 35)
- Chippewa Indians - History (Box 35)
- Chippewa Indians - Legal Documents (Box 35)
- Chippewa Indians - Rites, Ceremonies (Box 35)
- Chippewa Indians - Social Life and Customs (Box 35)
- Chippewa Indians - Tribal Government (Box 35)
- Chiriguano Indians (Bolivia) (Box 35)
- Chitimacha Indians (Box 35)
- Choctaw Indians (Muskogean) (Box 35)
- Choctaw Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 35)
- Chol Indians (Mexico) (Box 35)
- Chorti Indians (Mayan - Guatemala) (Box 35)
- Choroti Indians (Bolivia) (Box 35)
- Chronology (Box 36)
- Chumash Indians 1 (Box 36)
- Chumash Indians 2 (Box 36)
- Cibola, Seven Cities of (including Hawikuh) 1 - See also Vasquez de Coronado, F. de (Box 36)
- Cibola, Seven Cities of (including Hawikuh) 2 (Box 36)
- Cibola, Seven Cities of (including Hawikuh) 3 (Box 133)
  Marco da Nizza, A relation of the reverend father Frier Marco de Nica / touching his discovery of the Kingdome of Ceuola or Cibola, situate about 30 degrees of latitude to the north of Nueua Espanna, 1539, an extract of a letter of captaine Francis Vasques de Coronado, written to a Secretary of the right noble Don Anotonio de Mendoza typescript.
- Cibola, Seven Cities of - Articles & Corres (Box 36)
- Cigar Store Indians (Box 36)
- Civil Rights (Box 36)
- Clallam Indians (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment 1 (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment 2 (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Articles & Corres. (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Blankets (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Body Painting and Tattooing (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Dance Regalia (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Eastern and Plains (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Headdresses & Hairpipes (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Moccasins and Sandals (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Nose Ornaments (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Ponchos and Serapes (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - Pouches (Box 36)
- Clothing and Body Adornment - War Bonnets (Box 36)
- Cocopa Indians (Yuman) (Box 36)
- Code Talkers (Box 36)
- Codices (Box 36)
- Coeur d'Alene Indians (Box 36)
- Collections and Sales 1 (Box 37)
- Collections and Sales 2 (Box 37)
- Collections and Sales 3 (Box 37)
- Collections and Sales - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 37)
- Collections and Sales - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 37)
- Collections and Sales - North America 1 (Box 37)
- Collections and Sales - North America 2 (Box 37)
- Collections and Sales - North America 3 (Box 37)
- Collections and Sales - Payne Collection (Box 37)
- Collections and Sales - South America (Box 37)
- Collectors and Collections (Box 37)
- Colombia - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 37)
- Colombia - Antiquities - English (Box 37)
- Colombia - Antiquities - French - German - Italian (Box 37)
- Colombia - Antiquities - Spanish (Box 37)
- Colombia - Ethnology - English (Box 37)
- Colombia - Ethnology - French - Italian - German - Spanish (Box 37)
- Colombia - Geography (English, German) (Box 37)
- Colombia - History (English, Portuguese, Spanish) (Box 38)
- Colombia - Indians (Box 38)
- Colombia - Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 38)
- Colorado Antiquities 2 - See also Ute Indians (Box 38)
- Colorado Antiquities 1 - See also Ute Indians (Box 38)
- Colorado Antiquities 3 (Mesa Verde) (Box 38)
- Colorado History (Box 38)
- Colorado Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 38)
- Colorado Indians (Tsatchela) - Ecuador (Box 38)
- Columbian Quincentenary (Box 38)
- Comanche Indians (Shoshoni) - See also Folklore - Comance (Box 38)
- Commercial Enterprise (Box 38)
- Communication (Box 38)
- Community Development (Box 38)
- Computerized Bibliographies (Box 38)
- Computer Games (Box 133)
- Computers - Indians (Box 38)
- Conferences and Meetings (Box 39)
- Conferences and Meetings - Oversize (Box 132)
  An account of conferences held, and treaties made, between Major-General Sir William Johnson, Bart., and the chief sachems and warriours of the Mohawks, Oneidas, Onondagas ... Indian nations in North America, at their meetings on different occasions at Fort Johnson in the county of Albany, in the colony of New York, in the years 1755 and 1756. Photostats.
- Connecticut (Box 39)
- Connecticut - Articles & Corres. (Box 39)
- Connecticut - Antiquities (Box 39)
- Connecticut - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 39)
- Connecticut - History (Box 39)
- Connecticut - Indians - See also Missions - Connecticut (Box 39)
- Connecticut - Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 39)
- Conoy Indians (Algonquian) (Box 39)
- Conservation (Box 39)
- Conservation - Leather (Box 39)
- Conservation - Museum Issues (Box 39)
- Conservation - Painting (Box 39)
- Conservation - Photographs (Box 39)
- Conservation - Rug Cleaning and Repair (Box 133)
- Conservation - Textiles (Box 39)
- Conservation - Wood (Box 39)
- Constitutional Status (Box 132)
- Contributions (Indian) (Box 39)
- Contributions to Science, Engineering, and Medicine (Box 133)
- Copyright 1 (Box 39)
- Copyright 2 (Box 39)
- Copyright Information (Box 39)
- Cora Indians(Piman Mexico)- See also Language - Cora (Box 39)
- Corruption (Box 39)
- Costa Rica (Box 39)
- Costa Rica - Articles & Corres. (Box 40)
- Costa Rica - Antiquities (Box 40)
- Costa Rica - Antiquities 2 (Box 40)
- Costa Rica - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 40)
- Costa Rica Indians - See also Bri Bri Indians, Terreba Indians (Box 40)
- Costumes (Box 133)
- Cowlitz Indians (Box 40)
- Crafts 1 (Box 40)
- Crafts 2 (Box 40)
- Crafts - Alaska (Box 40)
- Crafts - Canada (Box 40)
- Crafts - Directories (Box 40)
- Crafts - Fashion Accessories (Box 40)
- Crafts - Ribbon Work (Box 40)
- Cree Indians (Box 40)
- Creek Indians - See also Language, Creek (Box 40)
- Creek Indians (Muskhogean) - Articles & Corres. (Box 40)
- Crime (Box 40)
- Croatan Indians (Algonquian) (Box 41)
- Crow Indians (Box 41)
- Crow Indians (Box 133)
- Crow Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 41)
- Cuba (Box 41)
- Cuba - Antiquities 1 (Box 41)
- Cuba - Antiquities 2 (Box 41)
- Cuba - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 41)
- Cuba - Indians (Box 41)
- Culture Areas and Tribal Distributions (Box 41)
- Culture Areas and Tribal Distributions - Articles & Corres (Box 41)
- Culture, Origin and Spread of (Box 41)
- Culture, Origin and Spread of - Articles & Corres. (Box 41)
- Cuna Indians (Box 41)
- Cuna Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 41)
- Curriculum (Box 41)
- Dakota Indians (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Arts and Crafts (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Black Hills (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Ceremonies (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Culture (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Economic Development (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Education (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Government Relations (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Health (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - History (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Land Claims (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Legal Issues (Box 42)
- Dakota Indians - Tribal Government (Box 42)
- Dances (Box 42)
- Dating - Chronologic - Technique (Box 42)
- Deformities, artificial - See also Baby carriers (Box 42)
- Deformities, artificial - Articles & Correspondence (Box 43)
- Delaware - See also New Sweden (Box 43)
- Delaware - Antiquities (Box 43)
- Delaware Indians (Algonquian) - See also Folklore - Deleware; Language - Deleware (Box 43)
- Delaware Indians - Articles & Correspondence 1 (Box 43)
- Delaware Indians - Articles & Correspondence 2 (Box 43)
- Delaware Indians - Articles & Correspondence 3 (Box 43)
- Denominational Indian Offices (Box 132)
- Delaware Indians - Legal documents (Box 43)
- Department of the Interior (Box 43)
- Department of the Interior - Press Releases (Box 133)
- Diegueno Indians - Articles & Corresp. - See also Folkore - Diegueno; Language Diegueno (Box 43)
- Dighton Rock (Box 43)
- Directories (Box 43)
- Dissertation (Box 43)
- District of Columbia (Box 43)
- Dogrib, Indians (Athapascan) (Box 43)
- Dolls (Box 43)
- Dominican Republic (Box 43)
- Drama (Box 43)
- Dream Catcher (Box 43)
- Dutch Guiana (Box 43)
- Dutch Guiana - Antiquities (Box 43)
- Dutch Guiana - Indians - See also Bush Negros (Box 43)
- Dwamish Indians (Salish) (Box 43)
- Dwellings 1 (Box 43)
- Dwellings 2 (Box 43)
- Dwellings - Articles & Corres. (Box 43)
- Dyes and Dying (Box 43)
- Dyes and Dying - Articles & Corres. (Box 43)
- Eastern United States (Box 44)
- Ecology (Box 44)
- Economic Conditions (Box 44)
- Economics, Economic Development, Economy 1 (Box 44)
- Economics, Economic Development, Economy 2 (Box 44)
- Economics, Economic Development, Economy - Artilces & Corres. (Box 44)
- Ecuador (Box 44)
- Ecuador - Articles & Corres. (Box 44)
- Ecuador - Antiquities 1 (Box 45)
- Ecuador - Antiquities 2 (Box 45)
- Ecuador - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 45)
- Ecuador - Indians (Box 45)
- Ecuador - Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 45)
- Education 1 (Box 45)
- Education 2 (Box 45)
- Education - 1800 - 1899 (Box 45)
- Education - 1900's (Box 45)
- Education - 1910's (Box 45)
- Education - 1920's (Box 45)
- Education - 1930's (Box 45)
- Education - 1940's (Box 45)
- Education - 1950's (Box 45)
- Education - 1960's (Box 45)
- Education - 1970's (Box 46)
- Education - 1980's (Box 46)
- Education - 1990's (Box 46)
- Education - 2000's (Box 46)
- Education - Alaska (Box 46)
- Education - South America (Box 46)
- El Salvador (Box 46)
- Employment (Box 46)
- Energy (Box 46)
- Environmental issues (Box 46)
- Erie Indians (Box 46)
- Eskimos 1 (Box 46)
- Eskimos 2 (Box 46)
- Eskimos 3 (Box 132)
- Eskimos - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 46)
- Eskimos - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 46)
- Eskimos - Antiquities (Box 46)
- Eskimos - Art (Box 46)
- Eskimos - Canada (Box 46)
- Esselen Indians (Box 46)
- Ethnoastronomy (Box 46)
- Ethnobotany 1 (Box 47)
- Ethnobotany 2 (Box 47)
- Ethnobotany - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 47)
- Ethnobotany - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 47)
- Ethnohistory (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. A - F (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. G - K (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. L - R (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. S - Z (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, American Indian Community House (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. - Centennial Exposition (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. - Emmerich (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. - Expositions of Indian Tribal Arts (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. - Gallery 10 (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. - Latin American Exposition (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. - Scottsdale (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. - Sotheby Park Bernet Gallery (Box 47)
- Exhibitions, Galleries, etc. - World's Columbian Exposition (Box 48)
- Expeditions (Box 48)
- Expeditions - Articles & Corres. (Box 48)
- Expeditions - Hemenway (Box 48)
- Expeditions - Hemenway - Articles & Corres. (Box 48)
- Expeditions - Jesup North Pacific Expeditions (Box 48)
- Expeditions - Lewis and Clark (Box 48)
- Expeditions - Rodman Wanamaker Expedition (Box 48)
- Expeditions - Susquehana (Box 48)
- Expeditions - Thule Expeditions (Box 48)
- Fashion (Box 48)
- Feathers (Box 48)
- Feather and Quillwork (Box 48)
- Feather and Quillwork - Bibliography (Box 48)
- Feather and Quillwork - Mexico (Box 48)
- Feather and Quillwork - North America (Box 48)
- Feather and Quillwork - South America (Box 48)
- Federal Acknowledgement Project - Recognition (Box 48)
- Federal Indian Policies (Box 132)
  Colonist period through early 1970s
- Festivals (Box 132)
- Field Schools (Box 48)
- Film and Video (Box 48)
- Films (Box 48)
- Fishing (Box 48)
- Fishing and Hunting (Box 48)
- Fishing Rights (Box 48)
- Five Civilized Tribes (Box 48)
- Flathead Indians (Box 49)
- Flathead Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 49)
- Florida (Box 49)
- Florida - Articles & Corres. (Box 49)
- Florida - Antiquities 1 (Box 49)
- Florida - Antiquities 2 (Box 49)
- Florida - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 49)
- Florida - History (Box 49)
- Florida - Indians - See also Missions - Florida (Box 49)
- Florida - Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 49)
- Folklore 1 (Box 49)
- Folklore 2 (Box 49)
- Folklore 3 (Box 49)
- Folklore 4 (Box 50)
- Folklore - Articles and Corres. (Box 50)
- Folklore - Abenaki (Box 50)
- Folklore - Alaska (Box 50)